Dearly Beloved, we are gathered here to honor the life of the end of my lock.
It wanted to be free.
I've got to be free.
Alright, we're off.
The world can't give it to me.
This medicine night.
The world didn't bring it to me.
So, we're bringing the staff.
In the future.
This is the head of the nurses of the hospital.
Dr. Roberto, who is the director of assistance.
By director of diagnosis.
This is Laritza.
Laritza is one of our nurses.
My name is Aleja. I'm the director of the hospital.
Alright.
So, Hiram, what are we about to do?
Go talk to the medical staff here at the pediatric hospital.
Learn about what they do, the work they do here, and ask questions.
Fishnets have been the vibe for a long time. Very long time.
Right?
I love it.
Revolution is everywhere you turn.
Her hospital has been really brutal.
And it has had a very great impact.
It is very difficult for the hospital to accomplish all its tasks.
So, last year we closed with about 3,000 seniors.
Wow.
So, the usual is about 10,000.
And it's those who can take the risk.
We sing this on the streets.
To those who are vulnerable.
And it's literally hold on.
Those are the two words.
And these are two words.
That means, wait.
Hold on.
Hold.
My dear Cuba.
We're on the freedom side.
Which side are you on, my people?
Which side are you on?
We're on the freedom side.
So, these are some of our fabulous med students in Cuba.
We've got Richmond right here.
We've got Philly right here.
We've got the Chi right here.
Say your names, loves.
My name is Colette.
Who am I?
Lisenia.
Jessie.
And so, I had just asked, and I realized I could record this.
What made you want to go to Cuba for your training?
The kind of doctor I wanted to become.
Doctors, no.
I feel like my mom has told people that her daughter at the school in Cuba.
And they've been like, oh, Cuba?
They produce really good doctors.
Uh-huh.
And so, for the people who know, know.
For me, my dad is the one who kind of told me about the program.
Because he's from Ghana.
Okay.
And the place that he's from, there's Cuban doctors working there.
Yes.
So, he knows, like, from his own experience, he knew that they were going to be, they were
going to train us well here.
You know what I'm hearing that I love from y'all is that your curiosity was peaked from all
different places, but all of you all said, let me go research further.
Which is also why you're going to be a good doctor.
Yeah.
Okay.
You're a good doctor.
Yeah.
Hey.
Hey!
Go.
I'm gonna go.
is, I'm saying like
8 out of 10
are giving me a case.
So, are you guys worried about
you know,
just the recent
aggression
from the American government
but also like how has it affected
you guys here and your studies?
Yeah, we are definitely worried. We're worried about
the future of Cuba. I feel like the US
is literally being bullied to Cuba.
There was a message sent out yesterday
about all the shipments, all the ships
of oils that they have stolen
from Cuba. So, we literally have not had
import of oil in three months.
And so, the country literally cannot
survive like that. And so, for there
to be this rhetoric that socialism is failing,
that the revolution has failed is just
incorrect when the US is
constantly aggressively
tormenting this country.
Like, how has being here
expanded your understanding of socialism
versus capitalism?
Look at the brains
working.
Look at the brains working!
I feel like there's a difference between
reading it and experiencing it here
in Cuba. I feel like, not just Cuba,
I just feel like anywhere.
I think one thing that they do well,
especially in this program, is
there is not this separation of
foreign students and Cubans.
Like, you're literally in there
with the Cubans.
Like, we're struggling with the Cubans.
If there's no electricity, there's no
electricity for all of us.
If there's no food, there's no food.
So, I feel like
you get a hands-on experience
because you're literally, like,
in the midst.
In the midst.
Awesome.
And how were you made aware of
socialism before coming here?
In your studies?
Like, is it from your families?
Yeah, my own is because I was in
the whole African people
draft-washed new party
before I came.
You better be in the whole
African revolution.
Yeah.
And I stopped because it's hard
to continue, you know,
studying and discipline
here, per se.
Yeah.
But, yeah, that's how
I was being aware.
But it is deeper being here
because you have to
maintain the social principles.
It's not something that
is just, like, you know,
global-based history
and then you have it
for the rest of time.
It has to be literally
each generation,
each group of people
continuing it
if that's what they choose
to continue, you know what I mean?
Yeah, it's definitely not just
the way the government works.
It's a way of thinking
of everyone
because, yeah,
everyone has technically
their rights in the industry
but it's also the way
to interact with everyone else.
So if I have a snack,
I'm giving it to everyone
in the thing that we work
around me.
If I, like,
my neighbor doesn't have,
like, oil
or rice
or sugar
or something,
then I will give it to them
because if I have something,
that means that we all have something.
So wishing you all the best
and, you know,
I look forward to just,
you know,
being able to be out here
in the world
supporting you
and the advancement
of your efforts
because, listen,
what we're going to need more
than I don't think
people even understand
is compassionate humans
like, but that actually
have training, right?
So that's you guys.
Get ready.
How is the arts involved
in the work done here
at the Martin Luther King Center?
Well,
I'll just say one thing
and it's that
sometimes in the struggle
in the way
we forget
what we're doing.
Sometimes during our work
in militancy,
in our organizing work,
we forget why
we're doing what we're doing.
And I can't imagine
fighting for a world
that doesn't have
art, culture,
beauty.
That's right.
Everything we do
has to go through
art and culture.
It has to be part
of the struggle.
Not only
as the important
tool that it is,
as the essence.
This is Eric's beef jerky.
Eric rolled here
with four bags
of beef jerky, y'all.
Hey!
Come on, white people.
Yeah, wait, wait.
Get it.
There you are.
Oh, that clap.
We're back.